- Previously on Gotham...
- I hope you know, Oswald,
you can always count on me.
Thank you.
Miss Kringle.
Dinner. Chez Moi.
Okay.
That's for Kristen.
Whatever happened with Tetch?
Broke his sister out of GCPD.
I'll never go with you!
- I love you.
- You're insane!
No, no!
No!
You killed her!
She died, he escaped.
'Cause I heard a rumor there's
something strange about her blood.
I'll tell you what you want to know.
You are gonna have to
buy me dinner, though.
He killed you.
Those who hurt you
will feel my pain.
I love you, Daddy.
I love you, too, baby.
I'm so proud of you.
Bye.
Well, the good part is about to happen.
I hope so.
Look at that.
There's no greater symbol of love
than two people who've made the choice
to spend the rest of
their lives together.
Hey, pal, we have a reception to get to.
- So, what you say we get a move on?
- Oh, yes,
about that... I'm afraid
you won't be able to attend.
This some kind of a joke?
No.
It's quite serious, in fact.
You're needed elsewhere.
Let's get out of here.
- Hey, open the damn door.
- Sorry,
we mustn't be late.
Please just... don't hurt us.
That's not my decision to make.
Your fate depends entirely
on James Gordon.
Hey. Hey!
Don't forget to buckle up.
- Sync and corrections by madhatters -
- www.addic7ed.com -
What a beautiful morning.
Sun is shining, birds are singing.
They say that fortune favors the brave.
They have that saying
in your country, Olga?
Ya ne ponimayu.
I don't know what you're saying.
Vash zavtrak gotov.
It's not important.
What is important
is that I have found someone.
What good is love if it's one-sided?
I have no choice
but to confess my feelings to Ed.
Da.
Now that, I understand.
It means yes.
My mother taught me that.
She used to tell me,
"Life only gives you
one true love, Oswald.
When you find it, run to it."
So that is what I'm going to do.
I'm also going to enroll
you in an ESL program.
You really should learn the language
if you're gonna work here.
So, I hear that Lee
Thompkins is running point
on Alice Tetch's blood at the GCPD.
That would make sense.
Can you get me a sit-down with her?
Oh, I see. You're willing to help me,
just not when it comes to your ex.
It's complicated.
Actually, it's really simple.
You just pick up the
phone, you dial her number
and you let her know that
Valerie Vale would like
a sit-down to discuss
Alice Tetch's blood.
See? It's pretty simple.
She won't give you anything.
You leave that part to me.
You know, I can get used to this...
You helping me with my stories.
We make a pretty good team.
Hmm. Does that mean you'll
share your breakfast?
Absolutely not.
But really, when are you
gonna give up this P.I. act?
So far you've had two
cases... One girl died,
and the other one, well,
you never found her.
In baseball we call that an O-fer.
- I'm happy.
- Of course you are.
You get to drink scotch all
day and have sex with me.
Uh...
I got to go to work.
You know what?
This is nice.
Let me know when you
hear from Thompkins.
Uh-huh.
Can I help you?
James Gordon,
Jervis Tetch has a message for you.
Follow my friend where to go,
to learn the truth you've hidden below.
Should you choose not to play,
precious people will die today.
- This is Gordon.
- Hello, James.
Jervis.
Never should have left that
hole you were hiding in.
Oh, I wasn't just hiding.
I put the time to good use.
Made a thorough study of you.
Quite the fascinating
history, yet so tragic.
A father lost,
career gone by the wayside,
failed relationships.
And here I didn't think about your once.
Oh, James.
I've been inside that
head of yours, James.
I've seen
the web of lies you tell yourself.
Strung together to keep that
fragile psyche of yours intact.
Well, it's been nice
catching up with you.
I'm going to force you to
confront who you really are.
And I'm going to drive you mad
doing it. Now, please,
direct your eyes to the overpass.
Meet Dave and Amy Walters.
Married just this morning.
Lovely ceremony.
In 30 seconds they're going
to jump to their deaths.
Take the stairs and you
can save them. However,
down the street there's a little boy.
His name is Shane, and he's going to be
hit by a truck, driven by my
highly esteemed associate.
Choice is yours James.
You can't save both.
So, who's it going to be?
You son of a bitch.
Good, now I have your attention.
They were innocent, Jervis.
You didn't have to kill them.
It was your choice, James.
You practically pushed
them off the ledge.
- Stay with me, James. James?
- What?
87 Fulton Street,
apartment 4C. Five minutes.
No police or more people die.
Oh, boy, now it's official.
Why, you looking to back out?
You'd have to put a bullet in me.
Good thing I don't carry a gun.
My father called.
He wants to throw us
an engagement party.
- Told him we're not interested.
- Okay.
I know you had reservations
about moving back here.
And you know my dad... Half
measures aren't his thing.
If we say yes,
he's gonna put us on
display for the whole city.
I understand.
But we chose to build a life here.
And I'm glad.
An engagement party sounds wonderful.
These go directly to
the city clerk's office.
And this...
Leave this outside
Nicky the Nail's place. Knock twice.
Light it and then run.
Okay.
Good morning, Mayor Cobblepot.
Good morning to you, my chief of staff.
Here are your schedules for the
day. This covers your duties
as mayor, and this as
kingpin of the underworld.
You really are settling into
your role here, aren't you, Ed?
And yet I still have so
much to learn from you.
Oh...
I came up empty tracking down Butch.
Somehow
that one-handed ape
managed to disappear.
I suspect he's hiding with his old crew.
I'm sorry for letting you down.
You have done nothing of the sort.
I would be lost without you.
In fact, um...
there is something that
I need to tell you.
Something very important.
What is it, Oswald?
You know what? I forget.
In and out of my head, just like that.
Don't you hate that when that happens?
That never happens to me.
You know what? I believe that.
So, uh, where are we off to first?
PS 134. You're touring a school.
Press will be there, so
we better get a move on.
Great. I love children.
Okay, thank you very much. Okay?
Hey, Cap, I just spoke
to that kid over there.
You're not gonna believe this.
He said Jim Gordon saved his life.
Pulled him out of the way of a truck.
Get him on the phone now.
I already tried him. No answer.
What happened, you forget your cane?
I don't need it anymore.
Put an all-points out on Gordon.
I want him found.
Hey, does that guy look strange to you?
I mean, more so than
the usual whack job?
Hey, pal!
You see what happened here?
I have a message for you.
James Gordon, I have a message for you.
- He's hypnotized.
- James Gordon,
- I have a message for you.
- Tetch.
Jervis?
Cutting it close, James.
Like what you've done with the place.
Everyone needs a hobby.
Take a peek through the lens.
Let's chat face-to-face.
I wonder, what is it that you
have against married couples?
Bad memories, perhaps.
Understandable, given the last time
you saw a woman in a wedding dress,
she had a shotgun pointed at you.
- Hey, Jervis.
- Yes, James?
- Hello?
- Don't you ever do that again!
Okay.
This is about your sister, isn't it?
In your addled brain, you blame
me for what happened to her.
Don't you talk about her!
I got to know her, Jervis.
She was a good person.
That's why she hated you.
Why she died trying
to get away from you.
You want revenge, kill yourself.
Dismissive, rude. I
don't like your attitude.
Well, tell you what.
I'll come down, and we can
talk about it in person.
Hang up again, she dies.
- What are you talking about? Who?
- Surprising, really,
given that every
relationship you've been in
ended in such misery.
And yet, you made the
choice to date again.
Poor girl. She had
no idea who she was
getting into bed with.
She will soon.
See for yourself.
Great thing about reporters.
Tell them you have a story,
and they'll meet you anywhere.
Got him in a safe house uptown.
You would not believe the
amount of steak that man eats.
Poor, Butchie. Nothing but
Tabitha and red meat all day.
You know, sooner or later,
Penguin is gonna figure
out who sprung him.
You need a plan, sweetie.
- I'm working on it.
- And in the meantime,
has the flame rekindled between you two,
or are you still holding out?
We'll see.
Oh, speaking of old flames.
Oh.
Well, you just can't seem to stay away.
- Tetch... where is he?
- How should I know?
And if you don't mind, Tabitha
and I are just in the mid...
Unnecessary.
Jervis Tetch kidnapped
Valerie Vale this morning.
He knew things that only
you could have told him.
I want to know where he is.
Oh. See that fire?
I mean, where was that
when we were together?
All I got was Captain Vanilla.
Seriously, we have to
open in a few hours.
- Then talk.
- Firstly,
I don't know where Tetch is.
Secondly, he may have come in here
a few days ago asking about you.
- Asking what?
- Oh, you know,
everything.
Family stuff, GCPD,
the women in your life.
He seemed especially interested in that.
He knew all about Vale
already, but I told him
about us.
About how you're still in love with me,
cry yourself to sleep at night.
And Lee?
Did you tell him about her?
Oh, you mean
Miss Rebound from me? Of course.
We'll send you a bill for the damage.
Lee, listen to me.
I'm sorry, James.
Lee can't come to the phone right now.
Can I take a message?
No? Good.
Gotham Water and Power, ten minutes.
I need to know she's
okay, both Lee and Vale.
What you want means nothing to me!
Nine minutes.
James sends his regards.
Now, where were we?
Oh, yes, introductions.
Lee Thompkins, meet Valerie Vale.
You both have one very
important thing in common.
You're two halves of Jim Gordon's heart.
James Gordon, I have a message for you.
Where is Jervis Tetch?
James Gordon,
- I have a message for you.
- Yeah, I know.
You said that the first
hundred times I asked you.
James Gordon, I have a message for you.
Where is he?! I know you can hear me!
Hey, Cap, a uni just spotted Gordon
pulling up to Gotham Water and Power.
Tell him to hold his
position till we get there.
Glad you could make it, James.
Where's Lee and Vale?
Oh, you clearly have no
sense for stagecraft.
We must build to the climax.
This is merely the second act,
where we stoke the tension.
On the right is one of
Gotham's finest pediatricians.
On the left, Channel
Five's favorite anchor.
A doctor and a journalist.
- You get it?
- Yeah, I get it.
The choice is simple, you see. It's kill
one, and the other will go free.
But if your answer to me is "no,"
a thousand watts into them will go.
Sorry, Jervis. I'm not killing anyone.
Yes, you will!
Now pick up the pistol and fire!
You want to show me who I
really am, then show me.
Oh, I will.
I'm done playing your game.
Jim!
Hold.
What the hell's going on here?
Captain Barnes, you're just
in time to see James kill
these two innocent men.
You need to find the
main power shutoff now.
- Go.
- Even when
you don't choose, James,
there are consequences.
No!
No. No!
- I'm gonna find you.
- Oh, I'm counting on it.
Just ask an old friend
how to get to the end.
This is our third grade class.
How many more grades
do we have to visit?
This is a K through 12 building.
- Twelve?
- Mm-hmm.
We don't have to see
every single class, do we?
Mayor James used to
read to the children.
Aubrey James is illiterate, ma'am.
- It's well documented.
- Perhaps we should move on.
What's wrong with that boy there?
That's Luke.
He's new here.
Hello, Luke.
I am Mayor Cobblepot.
Why aren't you playing
with the other children?
What if they don't like me?
Well, how would you ever know
if you don't give it a try?
And if they don't like you,
wait for them to turn their backs
and push them down the stairs.
Little guy needed a push. That's all.
I continue to be in awe of you, Oswald.
Ed.
There is something I
would like to discuss
in a more private setting.
Shall we say dinner
at the mansion, 8:00?
I'll pick us up a nice bottle of wine.
Tetch has
Lee Thompkins and Valerie Vale.
- You're sure?
- Saw him take Vale.
And I called Lee's cell
and he answered. So, yeah,
pretty sure. Call the M.E.'s office,
call her fiancé... Find her.
What the hell is going on here?
Tetch blames me for what
happened to his sister.
- He wants revenge.
- So, what,
he kills two innocent civilians.
- How does that track?
- He's obsessed
with showing me who I really am,
driving me insane.
He killed them, and I just stood there.
What were you supposed to do,
shoot one of 'em? You
did what you could.
That's on him.
This is just to prepare me.
He's gonna make me choose.
He's gonna put me in
front of Lee and Vale,
and he's gonna make me choose.
- And if I don't...
- He'll kill both of them.
We're gonna find her.
I promise you that.
Listen to me, Tetch is a lunatic.
He's gonna get caught.
The most you can hope for
is a lifetime in prison.
- Don't do this.
- Dumfree,
let's see what's in the kitchen.
Mm-hmm.
Nice try.
So why'd they bring
us back to your place?
Like I know.
Well, any chance your
boyfriend might come home?
Not likely.
You do know what this
is about, don't you?
Yes. Tetch blames Jim for his sister,
and we're his means for revenge.
- I've been here before.
- That's too big.
It's never gonna spring the mechanism.
You know, it is kind of ironic though.
I was just asking Jim to get
me a sit-down with you, and...
- here we are.
- Uh-huh.
See, I'm running a story
on Alice Tetch's blood.
I know you're running
point for the GCPD.
You're not seriously trying to
interview me right now, are you?
Jim said you wouldn't talk to me.
And he was right.
I think he was just
being protective of you.
Anyway, about Alice Tetch,
I hear they're running
experiments on her blood
at the GCPD bio facility.
- Care to comment?
- Maybe you're just really sacred
and this is your way of coping,
or maybe you're just insanely
committed to your job.
Either way, all I'm interested
in is getting out of here.
Try a cuticle pusher.
My dad was a cop... Taught
me how to pick locks.
I can walk you through it.
Thank you.
And in exchange, you can
talk to me about Alice Tetch.
You and Jim are made for each other.
Thanks.
It's not a compliment.
Thank you, Dr. Calvi. I'll call
you as soon as we hear anything.
Mario's been in surgery all morning.
Says that he and Lee left the
house together this morning.
She was headed to the station.
He hasn't heard from her since.
Jervis must have grabbed
her before she got here.
What's his next move?
Tetch wants me to find him.
Well, if that's the case, then
why didn't he just tell you
- where he is?
- I don't know.
But the last thing he said was
something about an old friend
leading me to him.
Well, I'm not just
gonna sit here and wait
for Tetch to send you an invitation.
Listen up!
Jervis Tetch thinks that Gotham
is his personal playground.
He's taken innocent lives.
And now he has Lee
Thompkins and Valerie Vale.
And to whoever puts the collar on Tetch,
my personal gratitude
and best bottle of brown.
Now go to work.
Follow my friend where to go.
James Gordon, I have a message for you.
James Gordon,
- I have a message for you.
- Hey.
James Gordon.
- I have a message for you.
- How do I get to the end?
"The true test will be revealed.
"A final decision you must yield.
"Our tea party begins once more...
when you walk through
Lee Thompkins' door."
- Jim.
- Not now.
What the hell is going on? Where's Lee?
Look, you're just
gonna have to trust me.
Trust you? According to Captain Barnes,
you're the reason she's
in trouble to begin with.
You know something.
You know where she is, don't you?
Keep your voice down.
Does Barnes know?
- Where is he?
- No, he does not know.
Because if he showed up with 20 cops,
both Lee and Vale would be dead.
I see. So you're gonna go
in all alone and save 'em?
Is that it?
Actually, you might be the
only person who could help me.
Come on.
- Remember, you have to feel...
- I got it.
Can I ask you something?
As long as it's not about
Alice Tetch's blood.
Why'd you move back to Gotham?
The way I hear it,
you made a pretty nice life
for yourself down south.
It's really none of your business.
Maybe not.
But you could have moved to
any city, gotten any job,
yet you chose Gotham
and the GCPD.
You realize that we both
might die today, right?
Mm-hmm.
Well?
I didn't come here for James Gordon,
if that's what you're worried about.
Not bad.
- My turn.
- Okay.
- Okay, so what's our plan?
- You're gonna break free,
we're gonna lure in one of these goons,
hit him over the head with something.
Not good.
Um, you can still get out of here.
I'm not leaving you here.
There's got to be something else
- we can use.
- My, my.
You two have been busy.
Now, if you'd kindly join
me in the dining room,
the guest of honor will be here shortly.
Welcome to our tea party, James.
We've been expecting you.
Please.
Have a seat.
- I think I'll stand.
- You'll do what I say
or things will get messy.
And by messy I mean
my two friends will pull their triggers,
and then we'll have blood and brains
all over this beautiful table.
So...
place your gun on the
platter and have a seat.
Really?
After all we've been through today,
you have to think about it?
Not everyone here has to die.
It's gonna be okay.
Don't lie to them, James.
Lee,
would you mind passing
that down to James?
I must apologize
for the hideous china.
Frankly, I expected more
from Don Falcone's son.
I guess I know what I'm
getting you for your wedding.
To good health.
I think I'll pass.
Me, too.
You know what,
I'll have some.
Bravo, James.
Now,
I'd like to begin by telling the story
of a brother and a sister,
separated for years but
whose love never waned.
Fair warning though,
it has a sad ending.
But I couldn't find my sister alone,
so I turned to this man, James Gordon,
whom everyone said was a good man,
an honorable man.
And what did this good man do?
Why,
he found my sister and
he turned her against me,
poisoning her mind.
And then he killed her!
Does that sound about right, James?
- Sure, why not?
- Now, James,
I get the sense you're not being honest.
Though that's not
surprising, considering
you've run from your true
self every day of your life.
But you can't run from this choice.
The woman you love is going to die.
I just need to figure
out which one it is.
So let's review our options, shall we?
On the one hand, we have Lee Thompkins.
Intelligent, kind.
She thought she could save you
from your darkness,
drag you into the light.
And what did she get for her efforts?
Hmm?
Pain and sadness.
Don't listen to him, Lee.
Look in her eyes.
She still has love for you, James.
And then,
there's Valerie Vale.
The intrepid reporter
from a blue-collar family.
She still has hope for you.
What will happen when she
learns who you really are?
So...
those are the choices.
Now it's up to you.
Which lady...
has your heart?
Who do you love?
You want me to choose?
Tell these idiots to lower their guns.
I don't trust them not
to shoot me by accident.
You're right. They are stupid.
Down, boys.
Now you drop your gun.
- And why would I do that?
- Because I'll shoot you.
Well, well.
You okay?
This was your grand plan, James?
Play along until Dr.
Calvi could sneak in
and shoot me dead?
Well, there's only one small problem.
Before you arrived, I
went down to the basement,
and switched the magazine
in that gun with an empty one.
My apologies, Dr. Calvi.
I only set the table for four.
Dumfree, will you please escort
the doctor to the bathroom?
I believe there's still
one chain in working order.
Now...
I'm out of patience.
Who do you love?
You want to talk about love, fine.
Let's talk about who you love,
- or loved.
- Don't.
Your sister knew you were crazy, Jervis.
Stop it.
She was terrified of you. She hated you.
- Enough.
- She told me...
what you did to her when you were kids.
The thought of you disgusted her.
Lies! Deceit!
The story you tell is incomplete.
She loved me. She loved you?
She killed herself
rather than be with you.
She didn't... no.
She impaled herself on a
spike and died in agony
because even that was better
than having you touch her.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
I saw her when she was dying.
Her face...
when she knew she was
finally safe from you,
she was smiling.
Because despite the pain, she was happy.
Liar!
She was the only thing I ever loved,
and you, you...
sent her soul to heaven above.
Yes.
That's right... me.
I'm the one you want.
So let Lee and Vale go.
Keep me but let them go.
Oh, James.
You're trying to confuse me.
But I won't let you.
No. I'm determined
that you'll live on and suffer
without your love as I have.
Choose.
No. I won't choose.
You will.
You'll certainly spill.
I'll make it easy for you.
On the count of three,
instead of telling me who you love,
tell me who to kill.
Or I shoot them both of them,
which would be such a thrill.
One.
Two.
Three.
Kill Lee.
Oh, finally.
The truth is revealed.
You chose Lee because you love Vale.
Very well.
I knew you had it in you, James.
All this time, you made everyone believe
you were the hero,
but deep down you always knew the truth.
You're a villain.
Vale.
This is Dr. Leslie Thompkins.
Please send an ambulance
to 25 Blackstone Drive.
Hurry!
Move.
You're gonna be okay, Vale. You hear me?
You're gonna be okay. Hold on.
Victim's name is Valerie Vale.
Gunshot wound to the abdomen.
BP's 100/60.
Tachy's at 160.
O.R. One's prepped and ready to go.
Clear the way.
Clear the way, please.
I've got her from here.
Ed.
A man comes to a crossroads in his life,
and he has to make a choice.
Does he choose safety and cowardice
or does he opt for courage
and risk everything?
I choose courage.
What I'm trying to say is...
The thing I've been wanting
to tell you all day long is...
I love you.
Impossible to pick the
perfect bottle, isn't it?
Well, it all depends
on region and vintage.
Of course, you have to
consider the wine pairing.
Miss Kringle?
No. Oh, no. My name's Isabella.
Um, I'm sorry to bother you; I
don't usually talk to people.
There's just, um, something about you.
No, no, please. There's...
There's no need to apologize.
You ju...
You remind me of someone
that I used to know.
A long time ago.
You struggle to regain me.
When I'm lost...
you struggle to obtain me.
What am I?
Time.
I'm Edward.
Edward Nygma.
Jim.
- How is she?
- Still in surgery.
She seems like a tough
cookie; she'll be all right.
What about Tetch?
We got the whole department
canvassing the city.
We'll find him.
Why didn't you come to me?
I couldn't.
And I thought I could save them both.
You did what you thought was right.
Maybe.
In the end, I did
exactly what he wanted.
He won.
We'll see.
Mario's a great doctor.
She'll pull through.
- Lee, about what I said...
- Jim.
Not now.
www.tvsubtitles.net